# **JOHN DARLEY**

077 1035 1743 | john.m.darley@gmail.com | E11 1JB

#### **summary**

An experienced Web Systems Engineer and Team Lead with excellent commercial experience providing third line infrastructure and support in banking, legal, medical and construction environments. Comfortable communicating at all levels. Has worked in all aspects of the Windows BackOffice suite, during the last decade has specialised in .Net and database systems. Strong experience of deploying and troubleshooting applications based on SQL Server and IIS.

Seeking a technically challenging role, similar to that held at Credit Suisse, with a strong desire to move into DevOps and cloud technologies.

#### skills

- IIS, .Net framework and related support tools
- C#, Powershell, VBScripting, HTML, CSS.
- DNS Administration, TCP/IP security & setup
- Good SQL Server, Microsoft Virtual Server and VMWare ESX
- Exposure to AWS & Azure

- Excellent communication and documentation skills.
- Microsoft MCSE Certified
- Agile Methodologies
- ITIL
- A strong knowledge of a range of network devices.
- Excellent problem-solving abilities.

## work history

### **Systems Support & Project Manager**

MMHG Ltd.

Jul 2014 - Current London

- Provided a mix of systems support, analysis and project management.
- In addition to support tasks I analysed working practices, performed a review of potential CRM systems then provided infrastructure setup and support during the implementation of the chosen system (based on applications linked within Podio.com).

#### **Website and Database Administrator**

May 2012 - May 2014

The Honourable Society of the Middle Temple

London

- Migrated and subsequently supported the Inn's website and membership database, formerly an in-house IIS and Oracle based system, to an externally hosted CiviCRM site.
- Responsible for the implementation of the eCommerce module to allow online booking of the Inn's lodgings, as well as specifying the integration with third party systems (e.g. updates with The Bar Council's membership system).

#### **Web Systems Technical Lead**

Oct 2007 - Jul 2012

Credit Suisse

Canary Wharf

- Responsible for the Windows side of Global Web Support in EMEA, covering IIS and SharePoint web farms and provided basic Linux support.
- Sourced, configured and managed roll out of Development, UAT and Production web farms in the UK. Project managed and technically led support teams in the US and APAC with their region's web farms.
- Profiled 2500 servers and applications, then liaised with development teams to migrate their applications to the web farm (based on IIS, Windows 2003-8, .Net Framework, WSRM and Side by Side technologies) for regional or global roll-out.
- Created Requests For Change and worked with the Networks team to implement the required load balanced DNS (Cisco CSS/GSS) names and firewall rules for both internal and external facing sites.
- Supported and trouble-shot applications using performance monitoring tools such as Symantec's i3 to establish where in the .Net byte code or TSQL system bottlenecks are occurring.
- Used MS Visual Studio and Debugger Tools to attach to server processes and step through problematic code.
- Setup and used Content Management Systems to perform application code releases from Development through

to Production in a controlled manner.

Provided performance and web usage statistics for management reporting.

Jan 2005 - Jan 2007 **Web Systems Engineer ORC** International London

- Provided operational and technical support for all UK websites, applications and server environments.
- Responsible for testing, UAT, documenting and deploying site updates successfully (clients include Saab, DWP) and HBOS).
- Setup website and application performance monitoring and alerts, including MOM and IPMonitor, producing management reports from the data captured Performed DNS and SSL Administration for internal sites and those hosted with external ISPs Setup, maintained and recovered MS SQL databases, profiling and troubleshooting database performance issues.
- Specified, agreed and coordinated roll-out of required firewall changes within the IT department.

**Systems Engineer** Jan 2003 - Jan 2005 **DEFRA** Surrev

- Provided 3rd line support for the multi-tier, IIS6 based internet infrastructure, troubleshooting and rolling out enhancements, including integration with MS Exchange, Active Directory and 3rd party applications (e.g.PDF middleware)
- Migrated applications from the single fire-walled, two tier, IIS5 based infrastructure into the IIS 6, clustered SQL 2000, double layer De-Militarised Zone, troubleshooting and resolving resulting issues.

**Web Systems Engineer** Apr 2001 - Jan 2002

Price Waterhouse Coopers

London

- Provided 3rd line support for an Internet E-procurement system based around NT/2000, IIS 5, Exchange, SQL2000, Oracle 8i and CommerceOne Marketsite servers, being responsible for server builds in the Development, Test and Production infrastructure environments (including repeat builds of 100+ NT/2000 servers).
- Performed hardening of NT and application servers and introduced enhancements to the existing systems and infrastructure, including SSL Certificate services, IIS load balancing, clustered NT, SQL and Oracle servers.
- Provided in-depth troubleshooting for issues with application enhancements produced by errors in HTML, ASP, Transact SQL or JavaScript code.

**Technical Director** Jun 2000 - Feb 2001 Polka IS Ltd Edinburgh

 Developed and refined specifications with clients to web-enabled their in-house mainframe and MS BackOffice Server based host systems.

- Developed an administration web, using VBScript, JavaScript, ASP and FrontPage, for all NT servers, users and groups contained within the website applications.
- Installed and optimised websites on MS IIS and WebSphere, continually liaising with developers to ensure maximum use of server functionality in their applications.

**Windows Consultant** Jan 1998 - Jan 2000

Ethicon Scotland Ltd.

Edinburgh

- Developed and refined specifications with clients to web-enabled their in-house mainframe and MS BackOffice Server based host systems.
- Assisted the developers during the testing phase of these applications, which included an award winning emailordering system now being deployed globally within Johnson and Johnson.
- Installed and provided third line support for the required BackOffice servers, including SQL Server, MTS, MS MQ, Oracle v7.x and Documentum.

**Systems Manager** Jan 1995 - Jan 1998 Vari\*Lite Europe Limited London

Developed a modular, company -wide data store to allow rapid application development.

- Implemented Exchange 5.0, with electronic forms, for network and remote users.
- Main duties as Engineer (1995-6) were to configure, install, maintain and troubleshoot voice and data network hardware and software.

## education

1994
Buckinghamshire
2007
Elephant and Castle

**Bachelor of Science: Information Systems for Business in Europe** 

**Brunel University** 

M.A.: PG Cert Digital Photography

London College of Printing